Jordan Whistler

whistlerjordan@gmail.com http://jordanwhistler.info in linkedin.com/in/jordanwhistler

Summary

I am a software engineer based in Eastern North Carolina with experience developing web applications on cloud infrastructure. I recently co-created Able, an A/B testing framework for deploying split tests to Cloudflare Pages applications using Edge Workers and AWS services.

Experience

Co-Creator, Able 07/2021 – present

- Created an A/B testing framework utilizing Cloudflare Workers and Cloudflare Worker KV for Jamstack applications deployed on Cloudflare
- Wrote a Node CLI application to install, set up and deploy services to AWS using AWS SDK/CDK as well as Cloudflare API
- Designed AWS infrastructure to deploy Umami analytics software and Postgres database to ECS and RDS, as well as utilizing VPS and Application Load Balancer
- Injected HTML scripts during split testing using Cloudflare HTML Rewriter API
- Automated deployment of worker script to handle splitting of traffic across *N* variants and serving appropriate static content from Cloudflare CDN while inserting appropriate test cookie and tracking script
- Automated the process of registering TLS certificate and making corresponding DNS entries on Cloudflare nameservers to enable custom subdomain through CLI
- Co-authored Able's case study at www.able-test.com

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

2020 - 2021

- League Management Tool A tool to assist a local organization in scheduling and managing rosters for little league sports teams built with Sinatra, PostgreSQL and HTML/CSS
- Jello A project manager inspired by Trello built with Node, Express, MongoDB and React/Redux
- Request Bucket An application for collecting and inspecting HTTP/webhook requests. Built with Node, Express and PostgreSQL

Skills

Javascript (Express, React, Redux, NPM, Handlebars) | Ruby (Sinatra, Rails, RubyGems)

HTML/CSS (Semantic HTML) | PostGRES | SQL | GoLang

Utilities (Git, Github, Linux CLI, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas, OOP, HTTP, REST API)

Education

Software Engineering (Capstone), Launch School

2020 - 2021

A multi-year mastery-based software engineering curriculum

BSBA, International Business Administration,

2002 - 2005 | Columbus, OH

The Ohio State University GPA 3.5

Organizations

US Chess Federation, Youth Chess Coach

2012 - 2014 | Marietta, OH